Pablo Sanchez Narro

sancheznarro.pablo@gmail.com — +44 7874932115 / +34 684710945 — • PabloSczn — • pablosanchezn — • pablosancheznarro.com

Profile

Experienced Software Engineering BEng with a First-Class degree, fluent in Spanish and English. Strong 'get things done' attitude, exceptional ownership, and deep engineering fundamentals. Proven in managing complex software projects and leading dynamic teams to exceed development standards.

Education

BEng (Hons), Software Engineering

2020-2024

Edinburgh Napier University, Edinburgh, UK

- · Graduated with a first-class average of 80%.
- Dissertation: "Exploring Explainable AI (XAI) Methods for Enhancing Transparency in AI Models"
- Acquired skills in object-oriented programming, secure software design, concurrent programming and agile project management.

Professional Experience

Software Engineer May 2024–Present

TaxCoder, Remote

- Joined a startup providing comprehensive tax support and expert accounting services through a cutting-edge online platform.
- Led the development of a web application using Python Django, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, and PostgreSQL on AWS, driving product innovation and operational efficiencies.
- Managed a dynamic team of 3, instilling a culture of problem-solving, proactive development, and continuous learning.

QA Engineer Sep 2023–May 2024

Infographics UK Ltd, Edinburgh, UK

• Managed Azure DevOps and implemented automated QA testing using xUnit and Selenium, increasing product reliability and reducing manual testing tasks by 30%.

Part-time position during bachelor's I was offered due to outstanding performance during the internship.

Software Engineer Intern

Jun 2022-Sep 2023

Infographics UK Ltd, Edinburgh, UK

- Enhanced application performance and resolved customer-reported bugs through optimized C# code development.
- Participated in agile development cycles, utilizing Scrum methodologies and integrating with MS DevOps systems for efficient project management.

Technical Skills

Languages & Frameworks: Python (Django, Flask), C#, Java, JavaScript (NodeJS, ExpressJS, ReactJS), C++, and basic Ada & Haskell

Tools & Platforms: Docker, AWS, Azure DevOps, GitHub, Linux, Kubernetes (basic), Ansible (basic)

Databases: PostgreSQL, SQL, MongoDB, NoSQL

Web Development: RESTful APIs, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, AJAX

Software Practices: CI/CD, Agile Methodologies (Scrum), DevOps, Automated Testing (xUnit, Selenium), Monitoring and Alerting (Sentry)

Certifications

Microsoft Certified: Azure Al Engineer Associate (Al-102)

Jul 2024

- Learned all phases of AI solutions development, including requirements definition, design, development, deployment, integration, maintenance, performance tuning, and monitoring.
- Integrated AI capabilities in other applications and solutions using Python, C#, REST APIs, and SDKs.
- Implemented solutions for content moderation, computer vision, natural language processing, knowledge mining, document intelligence, and generative AI.